Elden ring is a hard video game and
these bosses are no joke when you
finally beat a boss after initially
getting crushed then studying its move
set discovering where you can hurt them
it feels like you've actually achieved
something from software the people who
made Elden ring and dark souls and
bloodborne and sakiro employ a number of
tactics to gain the perfect level of
difficulty and sometimes they get it
wrong for the most part this game is
excellent you can study the bosses and
time your attacks so they land crisp
right in that punish window and it feels
fantastic but the developers are not shy
of using some sneaky tactics to derail
your run oh look there's another one of
those
[Music]
red okay
some would say sneaky others would call
this kind of thing boo in the base game
it was tolerable sure occasionally you
get squished by a giant ball that there
is no way you could have known about but
overall the game feels fair then the DLC
shadow of the air tree came out as an
expansion to the base game this DLC is
so enormous so deep and Rich and
gorgeous and enigmatic it is an entire
game in and off itself and let's not
beat around a bush it is a masterpiece
the whole Elden ring package is an
absolute
Masterpiece but and this is a large
voluptuous but with this
DLC they gone and up The
Bu there's BS everywhere here
teleporting backstabbing enemies this
horri maze building these guys but the
nonsense reaches a climactic peak right
at the end the final boss for a start
this guy has been resurrected from the
dead his attacks are so hard-hitting so
fast so definitively unfair I mean this
Comet thing he does as far as I can tell
it is completely
undodgeable
right we're close there he is here
what that what he's weak to almost
nothing glitches your camera every time
and has a boatload of Health something
has to be done about this so that's what
I'm going to do I'm going to level the
playing field with some of my own BS
there are three ways to be better in
Elden ring you can just get good at the
game you can get better equipment that
deals more damage or protects you more
or you can level up leveling up makes
you stronger allows you to take more
damage use more weapons and carry more
armor but leveling in Elden ring is hard
the price for each additional level in
runes increases exponentially going from
level one to level two costs just 700
runes but going from the penultimate
level to the maximum level costs 9
million it is almost impossible to hold
that many runes at one time you'd have
to beat the final boss 20 s over to gain
that many and if you die you lose all
your currency basically the game wants
you to get to level about 150 and then
just stop leveling up despite the max
level being
713 after level about 200 increasing
your level becomes so burdensome and has
such diminishing returns the game is
basically just saying listen that's
enough just get
better however the game does permit some
form of a agriculture if you know this
area welcome back fellow Farmers here we
have a bunch of sleeping enemies just a
waiting Slaughter right next to a spawn
point you can simply kill these guys
respawn and repeat and rack up the runes
so these guys here are all just fast
asleep and because this is a reasonably
high level area of the game
you can just kill them so this guy here
fast
asleep 2,000 runes per
kill however if I use this sword here
which you get actually ironically by
completing the base
game I can kill all of
them and
get 42,000 runes per cycle like you can
just reset run back and those guys are
all just
respawned ready to be
slaughtered with this sword so that's we
got 100,000 runes
already which naively you might think
that is a lot but if I go to
status that the runes needed for one
additional level is 246,000 at this
point so it takes a while to do this so
let's just do some calculations
here I have to kill
800,000 of those guys to to reach the
max level so there's about 15 of them
here so per run let's say we can get
40,000 that's about the average so
that's
40,000
runs assuming each one takes me 10
seconds let's divide that by would still
take me 111 hours like if I did this
absolutely perfectly every single time
to get to the max level the game is
clearly designed so that when you get to
a certain
point it just doesn't want you to level
up anymore it just wants you to get
better at the game and just play the
game to do this for 100 or 120 hours
would be mind numbing that's like doing
this as a full-time job for 2 and 1 half
weeks straight but with all that sweet
sweet cash 1.6 billion runes you could
have maximum health maximum stamina
maximum FP maximum um equipment load you
could probably run through bosses like a
hot knife through butter but who's got
100 plus hours to spare just to farm
runes well who says I have to do
it what if instead of manually farming
1.6 billion runes I could build a
machine to do it for me a machine that
plays Elden ring whilst I sleep and just
murders enemies for hours and hours on
it
that's it that's how I'm going to even
the playing field I'm going to get my
character to the max level but there are
some
stipulations I am a man with a moral
code I don't want to Simply cheat at
least not from the game's perspective I
want to operate within the rules of the
game so here are some of the statutes
that I must adhere to no software
running on the PC or Xbox or whatever
except Elder ring no sneaky extra code
running in the background no modifying
Hardware like mice or keyboards or
controllers got to be stock everything
and no mods to the actual game it has to
be vanilla Elden ring plus its DLC
essentially the game has to believe that
I'm just some sad act sitting farming
runes for a 100 hours straight so the
entire PC hardware and software must be
standard basically what I'm saying is I
have to build a robot so here we go this
is day one our zero so we need to build
a robot that plays Elden ring the first
problem to be solved is clearly how do
you push a button or a key I had an idea
that I could use solenoids these are
like little mechanical fingers when you
apply a voltage they can push stuff
solenoids can famously be found in
pinball machines but also everywhere
like car doors and hydraulic valves I
bought the smallest one I could find
since it only needs to press a single
key on a keyboard but buying small was a
bad idea that is that is
Toasty oh that's too hot to to hold we
may also have some other wiring
issues excellent build quality on these
solenoids the solution was a bigger
solenoid and using less power but in
order to control Power I need to use a
switch or in this case a
transistor I'm going to turn on and off
the solenoids with this this is a
transistor as a mosfit um I think
there's 19 billion of these in the
newest iPhone chip obviously they're a
lot smaller I'm going to use these as
switches to control each of the Sol noid
to switch them on and off and I can
control this with the Arduino
and after lots of fa we have our
mechanical
finger that's not hot at all and it can
press a key on a
keyboard yeah that work
nice next we need a way to mount these
so that they can hover over the keyboard
now I could learn to weld and build some
frame to hold the soleno over the keys
or become a carpenter and build
something out of wood or I could model
something and 3D print it if I had a
printer but then I realized I've been 3D
printing stuff without a printer since I
was 8 years
old this is my basic idea this goes over
the keyboard so the keyboard can slide
in here then the solenoid will be glued
onto this somehow and it will push the
key and I think we can give it like a
better a better base with one of these
should be able to fine-tune the height
of the solenoid by just adding thinner
blocks
on I think not the way to do this um am
I going to blow someone up here
[Music]
yeah that's definitely pushing that down
wait it down a little
bit that should be
better yeah look at that works so
well so all I need is six more solenoids
all mounted on the Lego and then some
code to time my game play and uh we
should be done
now we need six buttons as a minimum to
farm an Elden ring which means I need
six sets of electronics this Montage
makes it look like I know what I'm doing
but I blew up four of these transistors
by getting this wrong these dials stop
current flowing the wrong way when the
solenoids are Switched Off and these
resistors make sure the voltage goes to
zero when the system is off so off means
off then each switch or transistor is
simply plugged into the Arduino after
that the six solenoids are installed on
the Lego frame and with some minor
height tweaking we have built a robot
that can press keys on a keyboard all
right the build is complete and it's a
bit juny have a look this is a little
switch just to stop and start the
program so I can if it's going wrong I
can stop it um and it's not you can see
it's not actually glued to the Des um
but it is quite stable the Arduino is
not connected to this PC it should just
run by itself not conect connected to
that
[Music]
PC so that code there is just running
through each solenoid just testing if it
actually pushes down and presses the key
which it does but that is not playing
Elden ring so now we need to fire up
ring and see if we can time those key
presses so that it farms for me and make
it robust enough so that I don't die and
lose all the progress I made I'm also a
bit concerned that Elden ring has some
sort of system in it that checks for
like exactly the same key presses
repeated over and over again and like
kicks you out the game for cheating even
though I don't regard this as cheating
because it's a robot all right so I'm
taking a guess at what you need to do so
you need to run forward for about 2
seconds seconds then run left for about
half a second then forward again then
you need to attack which is T to convert
a Lego set that mindlessly mashes Keys
into a rune farming robot all that is
required is to perfect the timing of the
solenoids to Loop the farming action
over and over and
over and surprisingly this was extremely
easy to do this one is a little bit
this code is a little bit better so
forward left
forward 210 yes that's it that's it
that's the maximum amount of runes so
212,000 I can't actually believe how
quickly it took me to just perfect the
little button presses so that this
actually works but this robot is farming
for me right now okay I just went for a
coffee I've come back it's about an hour
and we have farmed 10 million
runes which is is is loads the game has
not booted me out yet so I don't think
Elden ring has a system for detecting
like identical inputs just running for
hours and hours and hours so I think I
can leave this
indefinitely what I'm going to do is I'm
going to leave it to run till tomorrow
morning hopefully the solenoid don't
burn out that everything stays intact
and I should have about 90 million runes
by the time I got
home thank God I built this in the
studio not in the house cuz this noise
is terrible
[Music]
okay so it's been 26 hours I got a
little bit held up I left it running
this whole time and amazingly nothing
has failed Elden ring hasn't kicked me
out the Lego hasn't broken the solenoids
haven't burned out the Arduino hasn't
tripped up and I have 182 million runes
to spend unfortunately I need 1.6
billion to max out so that is about 10
days yeah 10 times what I've just done
so I'm just going to let this run and
check on it every day make sure uh
nothing has went wrong and just keep on
[Music]
farming holy mackerel look at this
number here
996 million this we guy has been farming
absolutely nonstop and we are at an
incredible almost 1 billion runes you
can only hold 999 mil
999,999
runes so what happens when you get more
than that I'm not sure if anyone's
actually ever
tried because anyone in the right mind
would take all these runes and just
immediately level up so that you have
none left so that if you die you don't
lose
any oh I think we did it I think we did
it what happens now what happens
now we're maxed out we Max that what
happens
now nothing happens do you go you don't
get any
runes well that was slightly anti
climactic when you hit 999 million
999,999 runes you just when you kill
something you just don't get any more
runes it doesn't add it to your total so
you just stay at just one under a
billion runes but a billion runes still
isn't enough to level up all the way so
I need to level up burn those runes and
then
[Laughter]
continue we're going to farm another 600
million and Max this
out good job Little Robot you did a
fantastic job so the Rune farming robot
was a success it successfully farmed 1.6
billion runes for me so I'm going to
play this on my good PC at home and see
what it's like to play with a fully
maxed out level
[Music]
oh
now with a maxed out character it's time
to walk through the final boss like he's
nothing come at me
bro like that is
[Music]
unavoidable like
how do you avoid that perhaps I simply
wasn't warmed
up God that's such b run away from
these Dodge towards
[Music]
them like what like
ex well this abs a story of success and
failure stupid
camera sure you can make a robot that
can play Elden ring for
you like how am I supposed to work with
that camera how can I work with that
camera that's impossible and you can use
it to farm enough runes to reach the max
level
what that
what not this time
you but if you suck this game will
humble you
regardless of what you
[Music]
do yes
you oh
Jesus had to use the shield and
everything like had to go full on Noob
mode had to top up all the
health there you
go Elden ring what you do if you're like
me and prefer learning through problem
solving and by doing like I I did in
this video as opposed to reading or
simply watching a lecture then you
should check out this week's sponsor
brilliant brilliant is the learning
platform where you learn by doing they
have thousands of interactive lessons in
maths data analysis programming or AI
each lesson is filled with Hands-On
problem solving that lets you
interactively play with the concepts
this helps you build critical thinking
skills through problem solving not
memorization which clearly in my opinion
is the most effective way to learn
something I wanted to highlight was
Brilliance programming courses which are
a super easy way to build your
programming foundations and learn real
world applications what I love is that
you can start building programs on day
one with a built-in drag and drop editor
you'll learn essential coding elements
from loops and variables to nesting and
conditionals my code for this robot that
I built in this episode is very simple
but these are the things I use to code
it the foundational programming
Concepts all of brilliant's content is
made by an award-winning team of
teachers researchers and professionals
from MIT Caltech Juke Microsoft Google
and more so you know you're getting a
quality learning experience so whether
you are studying for an exam brushing up
on existing knowledge or just learning
so you can build a robot that Farms
billions of runes on Elden ring
brilliant has you covered visit
brilliant.org mikeb or scan the QR code
on screen now to try everything
brilliant has to offer for free for a
full 30 days days using that link you'll
also get 20% off an annual subscription
thank you very much to brilliant for
supporting the channel and thanks to you
for watching I'll see you guys next time
peace